<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>TheRogueVigilante's Space</title>
<link>http://naimish.xyz</link>
<description>Why do you need a description seriously?</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<item>
<title>the end of 10</title>
<link>http://naimish.xyz/articles/end-of-10</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
        Windows 10 is reaching end of support on Oct, 14 2025, a lot of people will be throwing away their computers or using an outdated OS even after it runs out of support. And the new version of windows doesnt supports processors that are just a few year old. Even a 7th gen i9 isnt officialy supported by Windows 11. The aim of this article is to tell people about the Free and open source options available in the GNU/Linux ecosystem. Read more about end of 10 <a href="https://endof10.org/">here</a>.
        </p>
        <p>
        <ul><li><a href="https://linuxmint.com">Linux Mint (GOAT)</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://debian.org">Debian (The universal operating system)</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://archlinux.org">Arch Linux (Style points)</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://gentoo.org">Gentoo (Get a life dude)</a></li>
        </ul>
        </p>
        <p>With GNU/Linux the options are endless, almost everyone uses a different configuration, and if you will ask a particular GNU/Linux user about his OS of choice some of his own biases will make their way into the recommendations, but I think most of the community agrees that <a href="https://linuxmint.org">Mint</a> is the best for someone who is just getting into the world of free software.</p>
        <p>If you have read this far, I would assume that you are considering the switch. Good luck and welcome to free software.</p>
        <p><em><strong>PS: Free software is not software that is available free of cost, it means software which respects the users privacy and its source code is freely available to change as per the user.</strong></em></p>
        <p>I am not affiliated with end-of-10. This article exists solely to help other people.</p>
 ]]></description>
 <pubDate>Mon, 8 Sep 2025 18:20:00 +0530</pubDate>
<category>Articles</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>the art of not knowing</title>
<link>http://naimish.xyz/articles/the_art_of_not_knowing</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>
        Imagine this you are learning something new like fixing your car, how to cook, switching from GNU/Linux to BSDs and suddenly in a moment of retrospect you see that you are doing well, and a thought crosses your mind, "Would you ever be able to learn all that <em>*this</em> has to offer?", in most general cases you come to the conclusion almost readily that "you won't know it all" and it's fine, because you just wanted to fix your car or you were learning how to cook this new dish, its not like you want to hyperspecialize in it and become something like a mechanic or a chef, and weirdly enough those field have their own hyper-hyperspeicalizations such as a mechanic might be good at fixing cars or motorcylces or a chef can be really good at cooking seafood or maybe he/she is good at cooking some other niche type of dishes.
        </p>
        <p>
        The point is modern day and age is filled with people who often <strong>hyper^(n)-specialize</strong> (treat n as a variable which depends on how <em>balls</em> deep you are into something) and sometimes I think that maybe this day and age requires individuals to be hyper^(n)-specialized due to the amount of complexity a general piece of modern techonology has, a basic device of the modern age such as a smartphone or a laptop requires a whole team of engineeres, designers to produce and that is when things like marketing and prodcut mangement is out of the equation and surely enough the modern man is better apt at communicating with other hyper^(n)-specialized individuals.
        </p>
        <p>
        When you look at it through a different perspective you see how this affects something, something known as a <strong>"POLYGOT"</strong>, a polygot is an individual who knows just enough about a lot of things generally speaking, but there is a better way to phrase this, a hyper^(n)-specialized individual might know the amount of things that he doesn't know in his own field, but a polygot generally has a better map of things that he doesn't knows in multiple fields and this is something which I call <strong>"THE ART OF NOT KNOWING"</strong>, the very thought of knowing the amount of things that you don't know feels very liberating, in a sense it shows you how insignificant you are in the grand scheme of Knowledge both quantity as well as quality wise, some might look at this and say, "But wouldn't it feel <em>suffocating</em>", I am not sure it might be suffocating, but to me this carries immense relief and at times I feel like the closer I come to knowing the things that I don't know brings me closer to <br>the <strong>universe</strong> as a whole.
        </p>
 ]]></description>
 <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
<category>Articles</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>what are tildes</title>
<link>http://naimish.xyz/weblogs/tilde</link>
<description><![CDATA[ <p>So whilst searching for alternative frontend's recently I came across something called tildes. According to <a href="https://www.tidle.wiki/tildeverse">tilde.wiki</a>, "The tildeverse is a loose association of like-minded tilde communities. If you're interested in learning about *nix (linux, unix, bsd, etc.) come check out member tildes and sign up!", in *nix based operating systems (~) tilde represensts the home directory, and in a similar sense the tilde's are a reminiscence of old multi-user *nix mainframes. When I first discovered tilde's it was nothing less than magical. I had no idea something like this existed on the mainstream internet. These are some of the tilde's you can try, if you are interested.
        </p>
        <ol>
            <li><a href="https://tilde.club/">tilde.club</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://tilde.institute/">tilde.institute</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://tilde.team/">tilde.team</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://tilde.town">tilde.town</a></li>
        </ol>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 23:58:00 +0530</pubDate>    
<category>weblogs</category>
</item>
<item>
<title>hello world</title>
<link>http://naimish.xyz/weblogs/hello_world</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="content">So as you can already infer from the weblog entry title, "hello world" the canonical entry of a novice or even geeks/nerds (I know they are slightly different) into new programming languages or domains, this log serves as my entry point the "CANON EVENT" so to speak for all us "ZOOMERS" out there to the day I started logging my stuff and my programs on the internet, for now I am going to keep this only as a strict HTML/CSS and maybe JS who knows if I would need it, anyways so this is going to be a strict client side content. You can think of it like a journal, or specifically future me, yes I am talking to you bro look at those two, "oo"'s in "look" not here the one in the previous "look", and remember that we have to be consistent with this.</p>

<p class="content">Also, maybe just maybe, I will add some api's here and there which would contact some server X somewhere for the purpose of learning and testing new stuff. Also I basically am a "noob coder", idk how far into the future, I would be able to carry this.</p>

<p class="content">So, last thing what is going to happen to this in the near future, expect some api's I don't have an idea what I am going to be using, idk if I am good enough to code barebones api's in C, I have made some beginners api's in node and python but they are kind of a nothingburger.</p>

<p class="content">OKAY, I should now get some crocodile tears in my eyes, *drum rolls*, I am ending this with a heavy heart. Lets, see what the future holds, come on get out of here, you can see I am very bad at writing.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 21:01:00 +0530</pubDate>    
<category>weblogs</category>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>

